RG 062:052, Town of Farmington
Connecticut State Library
Town of Farmington records
circa 1722-1940
Connecticut State Library
Farmington (Conn.)
29 cubic feet
Administrative, election, military, tax, school, court, and vital records for the town of Farmington.
RG062_052
T000351
Historical Note
The town of Farmington was named and incorporated in December 1645. The Town of Farmington, Borough of Unionville and Borough of Farmington were consolidated in 1947.
Scope and Content
Administrative, election, military, tax, school, court, and vital records for the town of Farmington.
Index Terms
Alternate creator:
Connecticut. Justice of the Peace (Farmington)
Subjects:
Elections -- Connecticut -- Farmington -- Statistics; Voting -- Connecticut -- Farmington -- Statistics; Soldiers -- Connecticut -- Farmington; Public welfare -- Connecticut -- Farmington; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Farmington -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Farmington -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Farmington -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Farmington -- Registers; Deeds -- Connecticut -- Farmington; Voting registers -- Connecticut -- Farmington; School enrollment -- Connecticut -- Farmington -- Statistics; Justices of the peace -- Connecticut -- Farmington; Writs -- Connecticut -- Farmington
Places:
Farmington (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Farmington (Conn.) -- Statistics, Vital
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, circa 1722-1940
  - Town meeting records, including calls, minutes, petitions, reports, orders to selectmen, votes, elections, broadsides about order of doing business at town meeting, 1774-1878 (Box Box 1)
  - Certificates of admissions as electors, 1841-1870 (Box Box 2)
  - Oaths and certificates of town officers, 1868-1892 (Box Box 3)
  - Overseers' appointments, 1772-1894 (Box Box 3)
  - Liquor dealer bonds, 1815-1823 (Box Box 3)
  - Liquor and tavern license applications, 1832-1888 (Box Box 3)
  - "New Burial Ground" records, 1835-1844 (Box Box 3)
  - Transfers of stock, company reports, annual statements of business, 1833-1888 (Box Box 4)
  - Military records, including Committee of Supply records, and enrollment, 1812-1880 (Box Box 4)
  - Election returns, 1793-1890 (Box Box 5)
  - Correspondence regarding care of paupers, 1811-1869 (Box Box 6)
  - Indentures and bonds for support of the poor, 1799-1828 (Box Box 7)
  - Board of Relief records, 1840-1896 (Box Box 8)
  - Grand lists or abstracts of tax returns as sent to the General Assembly or Comptroller, 1855-1894 (Box Box 9)
  - Tax Lists, 1817-1819 (Box Box 9)
  - Abatements and polls, 1825-1869 (Box Box 9)
  - Individual tax returns, 1826-1880 (Box Boxes 10-18)
  - Highway and bridge records, including correspondence, reports, surveys, petitions, writs, deeds, 1722-1880 (Box Box 19)
  - Bank and insurance company returns, 1827-1895 (Box Boxes 20-21)
  - Town deeds, 1748-1783 (Box Box 22)
  - Recorded deeds, 1753-1894 (Box Boxes 23-25)
  - Fire company lists, 1854-1884 (Box Box 26)
  - Board of Health minutes, reports, correspondence and certificates, 1887-1893 (Box Box 26)
  - First Ecclesiastical Society Fund records, 1821-1839 (Box Box 26)
  - Reports of stray animals, 1804-1830 (Box Box 26)
  - Dog registry, 1859-1892 (Box Box 26)
  - School Society orders, 1840-1842 (Box Box 26)
  - Reports of births, marriages, deaths and burials, 1851-1896 (Box Box 26)
  - Register of real estate transfers, 1871-1895 (Box Box 27)
  - Town accounts, statements of income and expenses correspondence, applications, warrants, constable's bond, reports, 1813-1896 (Box Boxes 28-29)
  - Treasurer's account with Park Fund, 1880 (Box Boxes 28-29)
  - Borough Treasurer's account book, 1901-1937 (Box Boxes 28-29)
  - Financial records of Henry Deming, Borough Treasurer, 1920-1940 (Box Boxes 28-29)
  - Cancelled checks, orders paid, 1824-1879 (Box Boxes 30)
  - Bills, receipts, and orders paid, 1781-1896 (Box Boxes 31-32)
  - Registry lists and voting checklists, 1836-1890 (Box Boxes 33-35)
  - School returns, visitors' reports, school district tax lists, Bills, orders, receipts, and instructions to the committee, 1812-1887 (Box Boxes 36-37)
  - Northeast School District register, 1850-1851 (Box Boxes 36-37)
  - Bills, receipts, indentures, crow bounty accounts, grand list, reports, petitions, returns, resolutions, legal records, printed town charter, justice of the peace records, road and highway records, and published annual reports, 1783-1935 (Box Box 38)
  - Justice Court records, including writs, certificates, Judgments, executions, 1775-1894 (Box Boxes 39a-42)